<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Projects on Angelo Corleone</title>
        <link>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Projects on Angelo Corleone</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 08:51:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://angelocorleone.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>3D Co-Op Game</title>
            <link>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/unity-project/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 13:53:00 +1200</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/unity-project/</guid>
            <description>
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#challenge&#34;&gt;Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of my university papers, the task is to create any kind of software product as a team. Any technology can be used, and the only prerequisite is that the project should be complex enough (for students) relative to your team&amp;rsquo;s size, and that the team must use Github for collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;response&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#response&#34;&gt;Response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we were a team of 5, we were told by our teacher that we need to build something bigger compared to a team of 2-3. We chose to build a 3D multiplayer game, and was told that it would be impressive if we can pull it off given the time constraints. The biggest issue I remember was we had a team member who did very little in the project, this person was not willing to exert the effort to learn and contribute. Below is our contribution chart when the project was finished:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://angelocorleone.com/img/projects/unity-project/contributions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Contributions&amp;rdquo;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue was that there is no documentation work that we can assign this person to, everything is software development, so I did all I could to carry the team. I learned a bit about how multiplayer is implemented, how interactions with the game world can be registered among players in a multiplayer game, how movement and game world interaction is implemented, a little bit of game design, level creation, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I taught the team what I researched, for example on how to collaborate in Unity using Github, which I learned the hard way that it is not straightforward in game dev compared to something like Perforce. I spent more than 300 hours on a 15 credit project to complete it with satisfactory standards. I was still lucky with some of my teammates though, as they also did their best in this project. I believe we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have finished if we had two deadweight members in that group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;result&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got an A+ on this paper while most of my teammates got an A, I was told by our teacher that our project was really good that it is being used as an example during the next semesters. I remember being salty that our nonexistent member also got an A, but that is life, I just focused on the fact that our team as a whole was outstanding, and produced a good demo project given the constraints. I learned a lot about game development in such a small amount of time, more importantly though I discovered that aside from playing computer games, I also enjoy making them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Microsoft Student Accelerator</title>
            <link>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/pomodoro/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 22:49:36 +1200</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/pomodoro/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; aria-label=&#34;Microsoft Student Accelerator (opens in a new tab)&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ANRCorleone/Pomodoro/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#challenge&#34;&gt;Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a Web based project using Typescript, React, Azure, and ASP.NET Core. This is required to pass phase two of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/studentaccelerator/&#34; title=&#34;Microsoft Student Accelerator&#34;&gt;Microsoft Student Accelerator&lt;/a&gt; internship I attended on my first year&amp;rsquo;s summer break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;response&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#response&#34;&gt;Response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly read about the required tech-stack - I studied a bit of Typescript and React during those couple of weeks (luckily I already have some background with C# and JavaScript which made this a bit more manageable). I did all this during classes and it was intense - I remember this task being harder than all my assignments at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;result&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky that the MSA peeps was happy with my project - I got an internship and that same company hired me as a contractor after that internship.
I remember being very happy when my teamate on that internship said I was technically skilled according to the MSA student partners :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Connect Four</title>
            <link>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/connect-four/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 12:18:34 +1300</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/connect-four/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; aria-label=&#34;Connect Four (opens in a new tab)&#34; href=&#34;https://airyndon-connect-4.azurewebsites.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#challenge&#34;&gt;Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a Web based Connect Four game. This is required to enter the Chingu team project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;response&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#response&#34;&gt;Response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used native JavaScript, some CSS and HTML for this project. As I was pressed for time while doing this, I used the ASP.NET Core boilerplate in Visual Studio. I believe that is a little overkill for a project of this scope, but I just wanted to get it done quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;result&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moderators at Chingu were happy with my submission, it was simple and working as intended. The comment I received was to remove those console messages we developers use in our source code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Middlemore Motel</title>
            <link>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/middlemore-motel/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 21:29:39 +1300</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://angelocorleone.com/projects/middlemore-motel/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; aria-label=&#34;Middlemore Motel (opens in a new tab)&#34; href=&#34;https://middlemoremotel.co.nz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#challenge&#34;&gt;Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebuild the website of Middlemore Motel. Make the site responsive and user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;response&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#response&#34;&gt;Response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple website and I want to use just the right tool to complete the task, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use a CMS as the client said he would rarely update the site&amp;rsquo;s content. For development I used – ASP.NET MVC, Javascript, and Bootstrap SASS. I then used Git for version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also used 3rd party services – SocketLabs, Google API, and Welman Booking Engine.
I then used an App Service and hosted the site on Windows Azure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;result&#34; class=&#34;anchor-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The client was happy with the outcome, the website is now responsive and has an updated look. Bookings can be now be made on mobile phones as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>