<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Angelo Ryndon</title>
    <link>https://angeloryndon.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Angelo Ryndon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 08:51:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://angeloryndon.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MSA Project</title>
      <link>https://angeloryndon.com/projects/pomodoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 22:49:36 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angeloryndon.com/projects/pomodoro/</guid>
      <description>View the repo
Challenge Create a Web based project using Typescript, React, Azure, and ASP.NET Core. This is required to pass phase two of the Microsoft Student Accelerator internship I attended on my first year&#39;s summer break.
Response I quickly read about the required tech-stack - I studied a bit of Typescript and React during those couple of weeks (luckily I already have some background with C# and JavaScript which made this a bit more manageable).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect Four</title>
      <link>https://angeloryndon.com/projects/connect-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 12:18:34 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angeloryndon.com/projects/connect-four/</guid>
      <description>View the project
Challenge Create a Web based Connect Four game. This is required to enter the Chingu team project.
Response I used native JavaScript, some CSS and HTML for this project. As I was pressed for time while doing this, I used the ASP.NET Core boilerplate in Visual Studio. I believe that is a little overkill for a project of this scope, but I just wanted to get it done quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middlemore Motel</title>
      <link>https://angeloryndon.com/projects/middlemore-motel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 21:29:39 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angeloryndon.com/projects/middlemore-motel/</guid>
      <description>View the project
Challenge Rebuild the website of Middlemore Motel. Make the site responsive and user-friendly.
Response This is a simple website and I want to use just the right tool to complete the task, I didn&#39;t use a CMS as the client said he would rarely update the site&#39;s content. For development I used – ASP.NET MVC, Javascript, and Bootstrap SASS. I then used Git for version control.
I also used 3rd party services – SocketLabs, Google API, and Welman Booking Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>